A Guide to the Papers of the Virginia Division of the American Assocation of University Women
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Virginia Division of the American Assocation of University Women 1962-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6305-e
This collection consists of ca. 300 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 1994 November 11 and made a gift in 2008 following the dissolution of the Chapter in 2007.
Biographical/Historical Information
Organization formed to "foster the development and maintenance of high standards of education, strengthen the fellowship among university women in order that their influence may be felt...in the solution of social and civic problems, [and] secure broader opportunities for women...."
Scope and Content Information
The papers include bylaws; financial statements; a handbook of the Board of Directors; a history of the Virginia Division from 1925-1970 by E. Marion Smith; information on branches; minutes of Board meetings and conventions; programs of the annual conventions; programs of conferences; reports of the President and the branch presidents; and resolutions.
Also issues of the "Virginia Leader" and "Virginia Vision"; clippings; papers from the "Child Care is Good Busine$$" project; and a joint brief filed in support of the United States in its case against the Commonwealth of Virginia over the Virginia Military Institute's single sex admission policy.
Contents List
- Bylaws of the Virginia Division 1970-1993 (Box 1)
- Financial Statements of the Virginia Division 1969-1993 (Box 1)
- Handbook of the Virginia Division Board of Directors 1979-1989 (Box 1)
- History of the Virginia Division, 1925-1970 1960, 1971 (Box 1)
- Information on the Virginia Division Branches 1969-1993 (Box 1)
- Minutes of the Virginia Division Board Meetings 1977-1994 (Box 1)
  (3 folders)
- Minutes of the Virginia Division Conventions 1969-1993 (Box 1)
- Programs of the Annual Conventions of the Virginia Division 1971-1994 (Box 2)
  (6 folders)
- Programs of Conferences Co-Sponsored by the American Assocation of University Women 1962, 1984-1989 (Box 3)
- Projects: Education -- Virginia Military Institute's Assertion of Diversity 1991 (Box 3)
- Projects: Education, Child Care 1986-1991 (Box 3)
- Publicity: Newspaper Clippings re the Virginia Division 1982-1993 (Box 3)
- Reports of the Virginia Division Branch Presidents 1988-1989 (Box 3)
- Reports of the Virginia Division President 1987-1988 (Box 3)
- Resolutions adopted by the Virginia Division 1970-1994 (Box 3)
- Virginia Leader 1988-1992 (Box 3)
- Virginia Vision 1978-1994 (Box 3)
  (2 folders)